<!-- Plugin Configuration File. Read more: https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/plugin-configuration-file.html -->
<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.github.wadleeduhwan.ghworkflows</id>
    <name>Gh-Workflows</name>
    <vendor>wad-leeduhwan</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
    <p><b>Gh-Workflows</b> lets you browse, monitor, and trigger GitHub Actions workflows directly from your IntelliJ-based IDE.
    Take full control of GitHub Actions without leaving your IDE.</p>

    <h3>Features</h3>

    <p><b>Workflow Browser</b><br/>
    Tree view displaying all workflows and recent runs at a glance.
    Each run uses a two-line layout: line 1 shows run number and commit message with status icon;
    line 2 shows who triggered it, elapsed time, and branch name.</p>

    <p><b>Trigger Workflows</b><br/>
    Dispatch <code>workflow_dispatch</code> workflows with branch/tag selection and input parameters.
    Supports <code>string</code>, <code>number</code>, <code>choice</code>, <code>boolean</code>, and <code>environment</code> input types.
    Required inputs and default values are displayed automatically.</p>

    <p><b>Status Icons</b><br/>
    Intuitive icons for every workflow run state:
    success, failure, in-progress, queued, cancelled, and skipped.</p>

    <p><b>Run Management (Context Menu)</b><br/>
    Right-click any workflow run to re-run all jobs, re-run failed jobs, cancel, or delete.
    Dangerous actions like delete require confirmation before execution.</p>

    <p><b>Failed Run Job Details</b><br/>
    Failed workflow runs automatically expand to show individual jobs with their status icons.
    Quickly identify which job failed and double-click to open it on GitHub.</p>

    <p><b>Open in Browser</b><br/>
    Double-click any workflow or run node to jump directly to the GitHub page.</p>

    <p><b>Favorites</b><br/>
    Save frequently used workflow URLs as favorites for quick access.
    Manage your favorites from the toolbar — add, remove, and open saved URLs instantly.</p>

    <p><b>Auto-Refresh</b><br/>
    Automatically refreshes workflow data in the background at a configurable interval (default: 10 minutes).
    Enable or disable auto-refresh and adjust the interval from the Settings dialog.</p>

    <p><b>Auto-detect Repository</b><br/>
    Automatically identifies the GitHub repository from your project's git remotes.
    Supports SSH (<code>git@github.com:owner/repo.git</code>) and HTTPS formats.</p>

    <p><b>Seamless Auth</b><br/>
    Authenticates using your IntelliJ GitHub account (recommended) or a manual Personal Access Token as fallback.
    PAT requires <code>repo</code> and <code>workflow</code> scopes, stored securely in the IDE's PasswordSafe.</p>

    <h3>Getting Started</h3>
    <ol>
        <li>Open a project with a GitHub remote</li>
        <li>Click the <b>GitHub Workflows</b> tab in the right sidebar</li>
        <li>Browse workflows and recent runs in the tree view</li>
        <li>Select a workflow and click <b>Run Workflow</b> to trigger it with custom inputs</li>
    </ol>

    <h3>Requirements</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.2 or later</li>
        <li>Git and GitHub plugins enabled</li>
        <li>GitHub account configured in IDE, or a Personal Access Token</li>
    </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>Git4Idea</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.plugins.github</depends>

    <resource-bundle>messages.WorkflowBundle</resource-bundle>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow id="GitHub Workflows"
                    anchor="right"
                    factoryClass="com.github.wadleeduhwan.ghworkflows.toolWindow.WorkflowToolWindowFactory"
                    icon="com.github.wadleeduhwan.ghworkflows.icons.WorkflowIcons.ToolWindow"/>

        <projectService
                serviceImplementation="com.github.wadleeduhwan.ghworkflows.services.GitHubWorkflowService"/>

        <projectService
                serviceImplementation="com.github.wadleeduhwan.ghworkflows.services.WorkflowSettingsState"/>

        <notificationGroup id="GhWorkflows.Notification"
                           displayType="BALLOON"
                           isLogByDefault="true"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
